# 今天咱们玩儿一邪乎的
We are going to play with something interesting
# 玩儿面了 不玩儿菜了
Play with some dough, not with meat or veggie
# 做一个家庭版的油条
Make a homemade version of youtiao (deep-fried dough strips)
# 做上早餐了 做上早餐 正餐也可以吃
It’s breakfast, but also can be eaten as lunch
# 这个面大约有一斤重 俩鸡蛋
This is about one jin of flour (500g). Add two eggs
# 这是个健康油条
This is a healthy youtiao
# 您做什么都是健康的 它里边不搁矾
Everything you cook is healthy. This version doesn’t add alum.
# 您真是站着说话不腰疼
Easier to say than done, huh?
# 现在腿好了是不是啊
Your legs are better now, right?
# 腿好了 你看见没有
Much better, you see
# 酵母五克
Yeast 5 grams
# 泡打粉 也五克
Baking powder also 5 grams
# 小苏打 五克
Baking soda 5 grams
# 这小苏打一般就是起外皮酥脆
This baking soda is to make the surface more crispy
# 泡打粉就是起膨胀
Baking powder is to puff the dough
# 酵母是发酵 谁家做油条搁牛奶啊
Yeast is for fermentation. Who else uses milk to make youtiao?
# 这成本多高啊
The cost is expensive
# 搁牛奶搁水是一样的
Either milk or water. They are the same
# 奶香味 现在放奶 放多少奶呢
Milky flavor. Now add the milk. How much?
# 放半盒 一百二十五克
Half the box, 125 grams
# 我先给它搅一搅 搅成啰嗦状
I’m mixing it first, into small strips
# 是不是还可以搁点奶啊
Can we add some more milk?
# 也可以搁奶也可以搁点水
You can add milk or water
# 一百五十毫升三两
150 milliliter
# 和这面就是基本上烙饼面 软和
This kind of dough is basically the same as laobing, it’s soft
# 好啦
Done
# 搅匀 也就是说水分比较均匀了
Mix well, which means the water content has been evenly distributed
# 我们再开始往一块揉
Then we knead together
# 二伯再给点奶
Er Bai, add some more milk
# 盐 五克盐
Salt, 5 grams of salt
# 一个盐是起味道
Firstly, salt is to add flavor
# 另外一个也起一个拉力（作用）
It also functions as a traction
# 盐有劲儿 有劲儿油条能拉劲儿
Salt has stretch, it makes the youtiao dough stretchy
# 吃起来有弹性
Tastes bouncy
# 选面基本上选低筋粉
When you choose the flour, go for the low-gluten one
# 不要用高筋粉
Don’t use high-gluten flour
# 大爷还真行 小活干着小腿儿也没事儿了
Da Ye really rocks! He does the work and his legs are better
# 网友们咱们祝贺大爷腿好啦
Friends, let’s congratulate Da Ye’s legs have recovered
# 叫他多做菜啊 不能放过他
Tell him to cook more, don’t be easy on him
# 这时候给它搁点油
Now it’s time to add some oil
# 你知道还得搁五克黄油
You know you need to add 5 grams of butter
# 我就不搁 我就这么任性
I’m not going to, I do what I want
# 大爷您千万别上套儿
Da Ye, don’t fall into the trap
# 今天咱们做的就是普通家庭油条
What we are making here is the homemade version of Youtiao
# 咱先不来这个
We don’t make it too complicated
# 这个时候多揣一揣
Knead the dough a few more times
# 把它和匀了 和滋润了
To make the dough even and moist
# 你知道我们做拿什么水和么
Do you know what water we used to make the dough?
# 茉莉花的水和这个面
We used jasmine-infused water make the dough
# 茉莉花的味儿很浓的
Jasmine flower has a strong flavor
# 咱们给网友点思路
We're providing ideas for our audience
# 就是给思路 就是一通百通么
Providing ideas, so that we can master the one to master all
# 最后再补五克油 他这说的什么意思
Lastly, add another 5 grams of oil. What does he mean by that?
# 老饭骨不但传承 还得引领他们创新
What we are doing here is not only to inherit but also to guide you to innovate.
# 没错
Yes
# 大爷在这儿做一个最基本的东西
Da Ye only makes something basic here
# 然后剩下的就让网友自己延续下来了
Then the rest will be inherited by the audience
# 今天的面真有劲儿
The dough today is stretchy
# 太有劲儿还不好
Too stretchy is not a good thing
# 但愿成功 一次性成功 没问题
I hope it works. Success with one try? It will work.
# 封上油 醒俩小时
Cover the dough with oil, let it rest for two hours
# 嗯 天儿凉
Eh, the weather is cold
# 网友们看着啊 大爷这儿出手了
Watch closely, Da Ye is going to start
# 这油条的面已经发好了
The dough for youtiao is fermented well
# 看看 行啊
Check it out. It’s good.
# 大爷做的是家常版的炸油条
Da Ye is making the home-made version of fried youtiao
# 大约三公分 大不大
About 3 centimeters. Is it too big?
# 别着急 不大
Don’t worry, it’s not too big
# 用不用给您拿个筷子啊 对是得拿个筷子
Do you need chopsticks? Yes, I need chopsticks.
# 这油条大 怎么办啊 改成俩
This youtiao is too big. What should we do? Cut it in half.
# 聪明着呢 真聪明 一捏
Brilliant. Clever. Pinch the end together
# 这案板太小了
This cutting board is too small
# 没关系您在家就做五根油条
It’s ok. You only make five youtiao at home
# 三米的案板你也不那什么啊
You don’t need 3 meters of the cutting board
# 咱们在家就在家么
We are at home, so use what you have
# 人家面板上全是油 您就搁面吧
Others put oil on their board, you can use flour
# 这（案板上）不搁油
Don’t put oil on the board
# 为什么咱这油条健康啊 没有那么多油
Why our version of youtiao is healthier? It contains less oil
# 我不瞒你说这油条
As a matter of fact,
# 到今天我才炸了第三回
Today is my third time frying youtiao
# 我也是学做 但是我今天呢
I just learned it. But today,
# 要把我学做的体会
I am sharing my experience of learning
# 跟我们网友一块分享一下
with our audience friends
# 你看我弄这个不像人家特专业的面点师
You see, the youtiao I made is not like what professional pastry chefs do
# 你这横着看像小船
Yours looks like a boat sideways
# 油条剂儿做好了 我们给它拉一拉
Youtiao dough is done. Let’s pull it a little
# 再抻一抻 其实咱们做面点不专业
Pull it a little to make it longer. Actually, we are not professional at making pastry
# 做面点专业的都是大小统一 长短一致
The professionals make the dough the same size and same length
# 我这个稍微的差点儿
Mine is quite not there
# 我这会让给弄得好看点
I’m going to make them look prettier
# 摆整齐了不就行了
It’s fine as long as you place them well
# 长了切切 这还不好说
If it’s too long, just cut it
# 大爷很厉害啊 厉害么 厉害
Da Ye is amazing. Really? Yes
# 第一个敢伸手 不是专业的敢亮剑
To be the first one to try. Not professional, but has the courage to show us
# 敢跟大家做分享
has the courage to share with the audience
# 可以下锅试一个啦 七成
It’s time to try to fry one. (oil is) About 200 °C
# 你看 对啊得杵上
You see. Yes, you need to stir it a little
# 怎么样这油条厉害了吧
How about this youtiao, isn’t it great?
# 行不行 太行了
Yes, it’s so good.
# 嘿还敢下两根 三根都没事
You dare to fry two at a time! I can do three at a time.
# 您下我扒拉
You put down the dough, I stir it
# 行了 好 这油条真棒
It’s done. Nice. Youtiao is so good.
# 大爷说了自己才做了三回 我不信
Da Ye said he only did three times, I don’t believe him
# 这人要聪明干什么都行
If you are clever, you can do anything well
# 我这回更聪明了 直接给它齐剂儿
I’m smarter this time. I’m making the dough into the same length first
# 这叫地道 这叫正规了
This is authentic, this is professional
# 终于大爷走上正规的路了
Finally, Da Ye is on the professional track
# 俩一夹 二伯出手了啊 筷子一弄
Stack together. It’s Er Bai’s turn, use the chopstick to press in the middle
# 一扽就行了其实 关东糖似的
Just pull it a little. It’s like Guandongtang (a traditional candy from the north)
# 好 这就行了
It’s done.
# 好嘞 灭火
Ok, turn off the fire
# 我们都吃这么多了 从炸到现在
We have eaten a lot.
# 我们都没停下嘴
We haven’t stopped eating since we started frying
# 实际上自我评价一下
Actually, as a self-evaluation
# 还有点瑕疵
It’s not perfect
# 一个是我抻的手法表面还不太光滑
One is because the way I pulled the dough is not professional, the surface is not smooth
# 不太专业 还不太专业
Not professional yet
# 但是我觉得基本上还算可以吧
But I think it’s basically ok
# 下次啊 再炸的时候作为课外题
Next time, when we are frying youtiao outside of the camera
# 炸的要比这回还要精彩
It will be better than this time
# 下次不能炸（油条）了
We shouldn’t fry youtiao next time
# 下次炸油饼了
We should try to fry youbing (another type of deep-fried dough)
# 我是大爷
I am Da Ye
# 我是二伯
I am Er Bai
# 我是三叔
I am San Shu
# 我们是老饭骨
We are Lao Fan Gu
# 欢迎大家订阅
Please subscribe
# 我们老饭骨Youtube频道
to our Youtube Channel
# 我们老饭骨组合
We are here
# 就是教大家做菜
to teach you how to cook
# 传授一些精湛的小厨艺
And to share with you some cooking tips
# 希望大家喜欢
Hope you like them
# 希望全球的美食爱好者喜欢我们
We hope that food lovers around the world like us
# 订阅我们的频道
Subsribe to our channel
# 点亮我们的小铃铛
Click the notification bell
# 同时在这里我们祝全球的华人
Here, we wish everyone
# 万事如意 恭喜发财
A lot of happiness and fortune in the future